Ted Berrigan Papers
Ted Berrigan Papers
1963-1964
Berrigan, Ted
.75 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet and editor, 1934-1983. Correspondence, manuscript submissions, and production records relating to C, a poetry journal which Berrigan edited. Incoming correspondence and/or manuscripts of John Ashbery, Imamu Amiri Baraka, Michael Benedikt, Jim Brodey, Joseph Ceravolo, Robert Dash, Edwin Denby, Ted Greenwald, Barbara Guest, Ruth Krauss, Gerard Malanga, Gregory J. Markopoulos, Frank O'Hara, Ron Padgett, Peter Schjeldahl, James Schuyler, Lorenzo Thomas, Sotère Torregian, Tony Towle, and John Wieners.
148847
Biographical History
Born in 1934 in Providence, Rhode Island, poet Ted Berrigan attended the University of Tulsa in Oklahoma. He was a second-generation member of the New York school of poets, and along with Ron Padgett, published a small literary magazine, C, during 1963 and 1964. He taught at Yale University, the Iowa Writers Workshop, the University of Michigan, and Essex University in England, and also served as poet-in-residence at the City College of New York. Among his published volumes of poetry are The Sonnets (1964), Bean Spasms: Collaborations by Ted Berrigan and Ron Padgett (1967), In the Early Morning Rain (1971), The Drunken Boat (1974), and So Going Around Cities (1980). He died in 1983.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ted Berrigan Papers consist entirely of the files for C, a journal of poetry which Berrigan edited during 1963 and 1964. The papers include a Subject file containing copyright certificates, distribution lists, financial records, and an essay written about the journal by Berrigan. The Editorial files contain incoming correspondence from both financial and literary contributors to the journal, and a collection of manuscripts which were submitted to the editor for publication. The Production records include the dummy sheets for no. 1-7, May 1963-Feb. 1964 for C.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radicalism; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Ashbery, John, 1927-; Baraka, Imamu Amiri, 1934-; Benedikt, Michael, 1935-2007.; Berrigan, Ted.; Brodey, Jim.; Ceravolo, Joseph, 1934-; Dash, Robert.; Denby, Edwin, 1903-1983.; Greenwald, Ted.; Guest, Barbara.; Krauss, Ruth.; Malanga, Gerard.; Markopoulos, Gregory J.; O'Hara, Frank, 1926-1966.; Padgett, Ron.; Schjeldahl, Peter.; Schuyler, James.; Thomas, Lorenzo, 1944-2005.; Torregian, Sotère.; Towle, Tony, 1939-; Wieners, John, 1934-; C, a journal of poetry.; American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Periodicals -- Publishing.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Editors.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase, 1964.
Inventory
- Subject file
  - Copyright certificates (Box 1)
  - Distribution lists (Box 1)
  - Financial miscellany (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts submitted - list for issues 2-5 (Box 1)
  - "Some notes about C" by Ted Berrigan, May 1964 (Box 1)
- Editorial files
  - Incoming correspondence
    - A-Z (Box 1)
    - Aldan, Daisy (Box 1)
    - Aldrich, Larry (Box 1)
    - Ashbery, John (Box 1)
    - Baraka, Imamu Amiri (Box 1)
    - Bearden, David Omer (Box 1)
    - Benedikt, Michael (Box 1)
    - Berkson, Bill (Box 1)
    - Brodey, Jim (Box 1)
    - Burckhardt, Rudy (Box 1)
    - Byron, Stuart (Box 1)
    - Caplan, Ronald (Box 1)
    - Cott, Jonathan (Box 1)
    - Dash, Robert (Box 1)
    - Denby, Edwin (Box 1)
    - Dupee, F.W. (Frederick Wilcox) (Box 1)
    - Elmslie, Kenward (Box 1)
    - Fainlight, Harry (Box 1)
    - Fraser, Kathleen (Box 1)
    - Greenwald, Ted (Box 1)
    - Guest, Barbara (Box 1)
    - Jensen, Alfred (Box 1)
    - Johns, Jasper (Box 1)
    - Kelly, Robert (Box 1)
    - Koch, Kenneth (Box 1)
    - Kolmar, Richard (Box 1)
    - Krauss, Ruth (Box 1)
    - Laughlin, James (Box 1)
    - Le Sueur, Joe (Box 1)
    - Levy, D.A. (Box 1)
    - Linder, Carl (Box 1)
    - Locke, Duane (Box 1)
    - Malanga, Gerard (Box 1)
    - Markopoulos, Gregory J. (Box 1)
    - Mathews, Harry (Box 1)
    - May, James Boyer (Box 1)
    - Merrill, James Ingram (Box 1)
    - Moore, Marianne (Box 1)
    - Morse, Carl (Box 1)
    - Myers, John (Box 1)
    - O'Hara, Frank (Box 1)
    - Padgett, Ron (Box 1)
    - Perreault, John (Box 1)
    - Picard, Lil (Box 1)
    - Rosten, Norman (Box 1)
    - Rothenberg, Jerome (Box 1)
    - Schjeldahl, Peter (Box 1)
    - Schuyler, James (Box 1)
    - Simon, Adelaide (Box 1)
    - Sonnenberg, Benjamin (Box 1)
    - Stuerman, Walter Earl (Box 1)
    - Thomas, Lorenzo (Box 1)
    - Torregian, Sotere (Box 1)
    - Wagstaff, Samuel J. (Box 1)
    - Weidman, Jerome (Box 1)
    - Wieners, John (Box 1)
    - Wilcock, John (Box 1)
    - Zukofsky, Louis (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts
    - Anonymous (Box 1)
    - Ashbery, John (Box 1)
    - Baraka, Imamu Amiri (Box 1)
    - Brodey, Jim (Box 1)
    - Ceravolo, Joseph (Box 1)
    - Dash, Robert (Box 1)
    - Denby, Edwin (Box 1)
    - Elmslie, Kenward (Box 1)
    - Gallup, Dick (Box 1)
    - Geldzahler, Henry (Box 1)
    - Guest, Barbara (Box 1)
    - Krauss, Ruth (Box 1)
    - Lima, Frank (Box 1)
    - Malanga, Gerard (Box 1)
    - O'Hara, Frank (?) (Box 1)
    - Perreault, John (Box 1)
    - Schuyler, James (Box 1)
    - Thomas, Lorenzo (Box 1)
    - Torregian, Sotere (Box 1)
    - Towle, Tony (Box 1)
    - Wieners, John (Box 1)
- Production records
  - Dummy sheets
    - no. 1, May 1963 (Box 2)
    - no. 2, June 1963 (Box 2)
    - no. 3, July/Aug. 1963 (Box 2)
    - no. 4, Sept. 1963 (Box 2)
    - no. 5, Oct./Nov. 1963 (Box 2)
    - no. 6, Dec. 1963/Jan. 1964 (Box 2)
    - no. 7, Feb. 1964 (Box 2)